<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mavlink>
  <version>3</version>
  <messages>
    <message id="0" name="HEARTBEAT">
      <description>The heartbeat message shows that a system or component is present and responding. The type and autopilot fields (along with the message component id), allow the receiving system to treat further messages from this system appropriately (e.g. by laying out the user interface based on the autopilot). This microservice is documented at https://mavlink.io/en/services/heartbeat.html</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="type" enum="MAV_TYPE">Vehicle or component type. For a flight controller component the vehicle type (quadrotor, helicopter, etc.). For other components the component type (e.g. camera, gimbal, etc.). This should be used in preference to component id for identifying the component type.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="autopilot" enum="MAV_AUTOPILOT">Autopilot type / class. Use MAV_AUTOPILOT_INVALID for components that are not flight controllers.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="base_mode" enum="MAV_MODE_FLAG" display="bitmask">System mode bitmap.</field>
      <field type="uint32_t" name="custom_mode">A bitfield for use for autopilot-specific flags</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="system_status" enum="MAV_STATE">System status flag.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t_mavlink_version" name="mavlink_version">MAVLink version, not writable by user, gets added by protocol because of magic data type: uint8_t_mavlink_version</field>
    </message>
    <message id="265" name="MOUNT_ORIENTATION">
      <deprecated since="2020-01" replaced_by="MAV_CMD_DO_GIMBAL_MANAGER_PITCHYAW">This message is being superseded by MAV_CMD_DO_GIMBAL_MANAGER_PITCHYAW. The message can still be used to communicate with legacy gimbals implementing it.</deprecated>
      <description>Orientation of a mount</description>
      <field type="uint32_t" name="time_boot_ms" units="ms">Timestamp (time since system boot).</field>
      <field type="float" name="roll" units="deg" invalid="NaN">Roll in global frame (set to NaN for invalid).</field>
      <field type="float" name="pitch" units="deg" invalid="NaN">Pitch in global frame (set to NaN for invalid).</field>
      <field type="float" name="yaw" units="deg" invalid="NaN">Yaw relative to vehicle (set to NaN for invalid).</field>
      <extensions/>
      <field type="float" name="yaw_absolute" units="deg" invalid="NaN">Yaw in absolute frame relative to Earth's North, north is 0 (set to NaN for invalid).</field>
    </message>
  </messages>
</mavlink>
